Did you know that in your gut you have a teeming colony of microorganisms?
你知道吗，在你的肠道里有一个充满微生物的庞大群落？
You have literally trillions of them in your body.
你体内有数以万亿计的它们。
They include bacteria, viruses and fungi, and are collectively known as your microbiome.
它们包括细菌、病毒和真菌，统称为你的微生物组。
And while some microorganisms cause disease, many are crucial to your health, helping your immune system, digestion and even your brain function.
虽然有些微生物会引起疾病，但许多对你的健康至关重要，它们帮助你的免疫系统、消化，甚至大脑功能。
The more diverse our microbiome, the better our overall health.
我们的微生物组越多样化，我们的整体健康就越好。
So, how can we improve our diversity?
那么，我们如何提高多样性呢？
'The single most important dietary factor we found for better gut health was the number of different plants we eat weekly, with 30 a week being the optimal number', says Dr Tim Spector of the British Gut Project.
英国肠道项目的蒂姆·斯佩克特博士说："我们发现，对改善肠道健康最重要的一个饮食因素是我们每周吃的不同植物种类数量，每周30种是最佳数量。"
This is because there are different beneficial chemicals found in different kinds of plants.
这是因为不同种类的植物中含有不同的有益化学物质。
30 plants might sound like a lot, but it turns out that unexpected foods, not just your 5-a-day, count as 'plants' too.
30种植物听起来可能很多，但事实证明，不仅仅是每天五份蔬果，意想不到的食物也算作"植物"。
For example, wholegrains like brown rice, oats, barley and quinoa, and legumes – that's food like lentils, chickpeas and beans, as well as nuts and seeds, will mean we get a whole host of microorganisms living inside our gut.
例如，全谷物如糙米、燕麦、大麦和藜麦，以及豆类——如扁豆、鹰嘴豆和黄豆，还有坚果和种子，意味着我们的肠道内会有大量微生物。
In fact, Christopher Gardner, a professor of medicine and author of a Stanford Medicine study of identical twins found that "a vegan diet can confer additional benefits such as increased gut bacteria and the reduction of telomere loss, which slows ageing in the body".
事实上，斯坦福医学院一项同卵双胞胎研究的作者克里斯托弗·加德纳说："纯素饮食可以带来额外的好处，比如增加肠道细菌和减少端粒损失，从而减缓身体衰老。"
But you don't have to become completely plant-based.
但你不必完全吃素。
Probiotics help the microbiome too.
益生菌也有助于微生物组。
These are live bacteria and yeasts that can be found in yoghurt and fermented food like sauerkraut.
益生菌是活的细菌和酵母，存在于酸奶和发酵食品中，比如酸菜。
And food from animals can have health benefits.
动物性食物也有健康益处。
Meat is high in protein and nutrients like choline, which helps with memory, mood and muscle control.
肉类富含蛋白质和胆碱等营养物质，胆碱有助于记忆、情绪和肌肉控制。
So, for better physical and mental health, grab those plants and strengthen your microbiome.
所以，为了更好的身心健康，拿起那些植物，强化你的微生物组吧。